Preliminary Inventory to the Bettis Alston Garside Papers, 1897-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
Bettis Alston Garside Papers,
1897-1980.
80054
Garside, B. A. (Bettis Alston), b. 1894.
4 manuscript boxes (1.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and printed matter, relating to mission schools in China, the life of the American missionary Henry W. Luce, communism in China, and post-World War II relief to China and refugees from China.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Luce, Henry Winters, 1868-1941.; Communism.; Communism--China.; Education.; Education--China.; Missions--China.; Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; China.; Missionaries.
Biographical/Historical Note
1894 Born
1989 Died
Container List
- EARLY YEARS
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1909-1913
  - U.S. Navy, 1917-1919
  - Boy Scout memorabilia
  - Arrival in China, 1922
  - Life in Peking, 1922-1923
  - Liang Kuo Ch'ang Hostel, North China Union Language School - Informal newssheets
  - The Peking Mandarin (publication of North China Union Language School), 1923
  - Stay in Weihsien, 1923-1924
  - Three years in Tsinan
  - Shantung Christian (Cheeloo) University
- BIOGRAPHY OF HENRY W. LUCE
  - One Increasing Purpose - Draft (Box 1)
  - Historic Chinese manuscripts
  - Publication of U.S. and Taiwanese editions of One Increasing Purpose
  - Selected comments
  - Selected comments (Box 2)
  - Foreword
  - Chapter 7, "The First Three Years"
  - Chapter 8, "Learning and Leading"
  - Teaching notes
  - Ecumenicity
  - Correspondence
  - Materials for illustrations
  - Correspondence related to publication
  - Memorial tribute to Henry W. Luce
  - Correspondence, Princeton
  - Presbyterian Board
  - Correspondence, Yale
  - MacWithey, Mary Linen
  - Luce family relationships
  - Van Voast, Helen T.
  - Luce, Mrs. Henry W. - Correspondence
  - Appraisals of the character of Henry W. Luce
  - Correspondence, General
  - Luce, Henry Robinson
- ORGANIZATIONS
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals (Box 3)
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China
    - Documentary material
    - Printed material
  - American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees
  - Christian colleges in China
  - China Conference, New York City, 1971
  - Committee for a Free China
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China
  - United China Relief (and its successor, United Service to China), 1941-1950
  - Riverside Church (Box 4)
- WRITINGS
  - Citations and awards (Box 4)
  - Address upon receipt of L.H.D. degree, College of the Ozarks, 1935
  - Roster of Old China Hands, 1945
  - Publications relating to American relations with China
  - Published articles by B. A. Garside
  - Unpublished articles by B. A. Garside
  - Speeches by B. A. Garside
  - Letters to national leaders relating to government policy